hello and welcome to another week of
Holo talk this is Frank defrota so I
want to thank you for tuning in we're
coming off of a pretty successful week
last week you may remember that we had
as a guest Alan Rhodey from
from House of Ross books who brings us
the holography handbook and the
holography marketplace
Alan also filled Us in on something that
many people on the internet found
interesting and that was Sony's new
holographic camera where it creates a
stereograms it's sort of like a portable
Cameron Alan filled Us in on many of the
details of that last week after that
interview was finished before I put that
up to the web and for everyone to listen
to I went on to the news groups not only
the ones that are interested in
holography like physics and Optics and
Laser news groups but we also had the
opportunity to go on to the photography
news groups as well because this is
something certainly that would be of
interest to amateur and professional
photographers as well the fact that they
now have a portable device that could
just automatically do holographic
portraits for them so I posted that
information as well and Alan if you're
listening I just want to let you know
that you've had the best show so far the
number of visitors that came on that
Monday to hear your presentation on that
camera with
1133 which is uh photography and
something that's as Fringe as holography
is now that's that's a pretty good
number for one day to listen to this
hollow talk show
the previous record holder actually was
Dr Benton from MIT and we had 1114 so it
was a close race but Alan you took it
1133 and I believe the next day was 700
and some and 670 as the week went on it
got lower and lower
is a nice
nice turnout for last week's show
there's not a lot of information this
week and I just have a few things here
jotted down that I want to cover with
you if you remember a few weeks ago I
mentioned that if you live in the New
York Philadelphia Baltimore Washington
D.C Carter that there's going to be a
laser and holography traveling exhibit
that's coming into this area that if you
live in one of those geographical
locations or along that Corridor or a
little bit on either side of that that
Carter that it would be an easy trip for
you to come out and see the show
the latest news I have on that is that
still may need another week before we
can
information on that it's still con
contractual Arrangements have have not
been made
in blood yet for this show so I've been
asked not to give out any information on
it as of yet which is okay and as soon
as we know we'll let you know I can tell
you that it is slated if it does happen
and things don't fall through for this
summer
and it is a major
National traveling exhibit for lasers
and Holograms now the thing that the
part that I'm trying to play in this
actually there's a number of different
hats I'm wearing with this whole thing
but the the thing that will affect some
of the listeners is the fact that I'd
like very much to have an exhibit
of amateur holography to go along with
the exhibit that will be there of that
professional
holography so if you're an amateur or
hobbyist then of course you know by that
definition your main source of income is
not holography but you approach
holography the way people approach
photography as a hobby and this will
include people out in the workforce and
also students and teachers as well
if you've done a few Holograms
and you would be interested in having
one of those Holograms exhibited
in a national traveling Exhibit while
it's here the Holograms won't go on the
road with it once you said it's finished
but once it's here drop me an email and
let me know and I'll put your email into
a folder and when this goes through
within the next week or so I'll contact
you and we'll make arrangements to have
one of your amateur hobbyists Holograms
in this show as well because I feel it's
very important
that the amateur and hobbyist
holographer is represented in shows
okay to move on another thing I want to
follow up on is the light craft store if
you remember this may have gone back
about two months we had a story on here
that there's actually
um a device a laser device which is
being tested out of I believe White
Sands Missile Range which launches
vehicles in the space using laser light
and this is not science fiction this is
absolutely true this is a joint project
I believe between us and the government
and the Air Force and I contacted them
and asked them if they'd be interested
to be on the show and he did get back to
me and they said that they would and
that they were going to have an
announcement to make possibly by the end
of February and the beginning of March
which it is now so I'm going to let this
go for a few more days possibly a week
and if I don't hear from them I'll
contact them again and get them on the
show because from what I understand they
had certain height restrictions out at
the
the testing grounds for launching these
vehicles with the laser and those
restrictions may be lifted
we'll get more information in on that if
you want more information well it's just
an email and I'll send that along to you
let's see next week's guest
and we have a surprise mystery guest
next week and this gentleman is a very
serious and uh possibly one of the top
collectors in the United States for
holography and what we're doing we're
going to have him on the show and have
him talk about the collection that he
has in some of his unique pieces and his
uh his pride and joy pieces and I also
want to talk to him and get some
information and tips for the listeners
that if they were interested in starting
their own collection of holograms how
they can go about doing it now it's
tough to get started with a collection
of holograms if you're interested in
very serious work because you can pay
upwards of ten twenty thirty thousand
dollars I would imagine for some of the
better holographic pieces out there that
have been created by some of the more
famous holographic artists
at the opposite end of the spectrum we
have Holograms that you can collect for
virtually nothing you know that you find
out there in that packaging and
advertising and Publishing so we'll try
and bring those two ends together and
try and get the best of both worlds and
get across to the listeners that if
you're interested in getting a
holography collection started what's the
best way to go about doing it I
published a newsletter for many years
from 1983 called the Hologram and one of
those issues which was the top request
for back issues was an issue which was
called antiquarian holographica
and it sort of got into the issue of
collecting Holograms so maybe we'll go
back into one of those back issues and
bring up some of that information as
well
okay believe it or not there were no
emails and no telephone calls this week
I did get a number of emails concerning
the show last week Alan Rhody said
presentation on the Sony holographic
camera
folks I don't have any more information
on it when Alan gets back from Hawaii if
he's listening to the show what I'll try
to do is get in touch with him and find
out how the listeners can get more
information and next week I'll let you
know about how you can go about doing
that in the meantime
did get a listing from Dutch holographic
Labs that they wanted their link listed
on my link page and I went to their page
to check it out and I have a very
interesting page I would suggest that
you go over to the link page and click I
believe it may be the top one in there I
think that's the last link that I put up
click on Dutch holographic Laboratories
and they have something which may
actually be similar to what Sony is
doing from Alice Allen's description
last week it sounded as if the Sony
system was quite portable and from what
I had a chance to see the one at the
Dutch holographic Labs page I believe it
was actually a table mounted unit or
something like that which the Sony may
be as well but in case you're interested
in following up on this hollow camera
stuff I imagine we may get a few people
left over from last week who have never
logged on before
go to my link page and click on Dutch
holographic Laboratories and it may give
you some sort of indication as to what
this technology is all about because it
seemed like very similar technology to
me
in any case folks
that's it for the show I don't have
anything to cover next week we'll have a
guest on so you want to log on for the
guest talking about collecting Holograms
we do have guests lined up for the rest
of the year
uh so I want to thank you for logging on
this time and I'll see you next week
take care